MANIKANDAN S

Sales Manager - ELV (Building Management System, Fire Safety and Security)

- Legend Anantara Apartment, No.12A, Married Flat F4, North Street, Ashok Nagar, Ganapathipuram, Tambaram East, Chennai, 600059
- +91-9629305962
- manik.s.17@gmail.com
- **17/05/1990**
- Indian

Having 9+ years of experience in Extra Low Voltage System. Looking to be a part of a creative team whereby my acquired skills and knowledge are put into use, thus contributing to the enhancement and productivity of the organization.



Skills

- Key account management
- Solution Sales
- Sales processes
- Technical Solution Knowledge
- Hands on Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)
- Customer Relationship



Work History

2017-04 - Current

Key Account Manager

SIEMENS Limited, Chennai, India

- Secured high-value accounts through consultative selling, effective customer solutions and promoting compelling business opportunities.
- Improved account management by predicting potential competitive threats and outlining proactive solutions.
- Boosted customer satisfaction by providing teams with training and skills to optimize service delivery in alignment with individual needs.
- Communicated well with broad range of professionals to promote Products and Solutions
- Developed new business relationships and maintained existing through

regular communications and effective account management.

- Prepared and deliver customer sales quotes.
- Presented professional image consistent with company's brand values.
- Achieved or exceeded company-defined sales quotas for the year 2019 and 2021.
- Quoted prices, credit terms and other bid specifications.
- Liaised between internal and external stakeholders, clients and various external vendors to develop and implement client solutions.
- Worked independently with minimal supervision.
- Negotiated prices, terms of sales and service agreements.

Senior Engineer -Presales and Design

Venba Tech Private Limited, Chennai, India,

- Presales- Preparation of Design Brief and Input Output Summary,
 Preparation of BOQ, Preparation of Estimation for the Project.
- Design and Engineering of the Building Management System and Extra Low Voltage System.
- To provide guideline of Integration during project execution
- Studying the Architectural Layouts to design the Safety System (Fire Alarm System & Public Address System), Security System (CCTV & Access Control System) & also studying the MEP services to design the BMS
- System Architecture preparation for the BMS and IBMS system based on the BOQ and project requirement



2012-08 - 2017-03

2008-09 - 2012-06

Education

Laucanon

Bachelor of Engineering: Electronics and Communications Engineering

Hindustan Institute of Technology - Coimbatore



Accomplishments



- Achieved an Excellence Awards 2021 on being awarded in the Category Largest Order FY 2021.
- Country Award FY 2021- Part of Team
- Won two times Employee of the month in Venba Tech Private Limited



Languages



Tamil



English



Certifications

2021-05

Datacenter Fundamental Program

